Thomas Glaser

20 Gallys Road, Windsor, SL4 5QY

020 8133 0543 - tglaser@vorwardit.co.uk

Profile

I have twelve years commercial experience in the IT services and software delivery industry. During this time I mainly fulfilled the roles of a Senior Software Engineer and Technical Team Lead. Prior to this I have successfully graduated as a Dipl.-Inf. (equivalent to M. Sc.) at the Technical University of Ilmenau, Germany.

I have not only an excellent track record from a technical point of view but have also received consistently positive feedback about my pro-active approach, outstanding communication skills and team work.

In addition to interesting technical tasks, a large part of my job satisfaction is coming from solving real-life customer needs and I enjoy ongoing interaction with stakeholders as only this ensures the best outcome possible.

Key skills: Web Development on the Microsoft stack.

Skills

Duramania I an ances		
Programming Languages		
C#	11 Years	
C++	4 Years	
JavaScript	2 Years	
Android (Java)	6 Months	
Markup Languages		
X/HTML	10 Years	
XML	10 Years	
XSLT	3 Years	
IDE		
VS 6 – VS 2015	15 Years	
Eclipse / Eclipse ADT	2 Years	
Netbeans	1.5 Years	
Data Storage and Manageme	nt	
MS SQL Server 2008 – 2012	4 Years	
Management Studio	4 Years	
T-SQL	4 Years	
Excel / VBA	1 Year	
Ingres RDBMS	6 Years	
OpenROAD	4 Years	
Continuous Integration and Build		
TFS	1.5 Years	
Web Servers		

Leadership		
Technical Team Lead	4 Years	
IT Director	1.5 Years	
Web Technologies		
ASP MVC 2 – 5, Razor	2.5 Years	
WebAPI 1 – 2	1 Year	
jQuery	2.5 Years	
AJAX	4 Years	
JSON	2.5 Years	
CSS	10 Years	
Twitter Bootstrap 2 - 3	2 Years	
AngularJS	1 Year	
KnockoutJS	1 Year	
Grails	6 Months	
Telerik GridView	3 Months	
APIs		
Google Maps JS v3	2.5 Years	
Google Maps Android v2	6 Months	
Google GeoCode	2 Years	
Twitter v2	6 Months	
Google Cloud Messaging	6 Months	
Desktop/Mobile Technologies		
Winforms	3 Years	

IIS 5 – 8	9 Years
MS Azure	3 Years
Apache	6 Months
BI/ETL	
Talend Open Studio	2 Years
Jasper Reports	2 Years
Architecture, Design Patterns	
Distributed Systems	N-Tier
OOP, OOD	MVC
MVVM	Unit of work
Singleton	Responsive Web
Code First	Database First
Methodologies	
Waterfall, Agile	
Ecommerce	

Lotus Notes	1 Year	
Android	6 Months	
QT	1 Year	
Windows Mobile	1 Month	
Source Control, Bug Tracking		
Subversion	8 Years	
Git	2.5 Years	
TFS	1.5 Years	
CVS	2 Years	
Redmine	1 Year	
Bazaar	1 Year	
.Net Frameworks		
1.1, 2, 3, 3.5, 4, 4.5, 4.5.2	9 Years	
Frameworks, Extensions & ORM		
LINQ	3 Years	
Entity Framework 3 – 6	3 Years	
Hibernate	6 Months	

Experience

Senior Web Developer (contract)

July 2015 - Present

Extending and updating Knight Frank's web presence.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP MVC, AngularJS, ASP WebApi, WebForms, Visual Studio 2015, MS SQL Server

I have written multiple extensions and fixes to the current website. Noteworthy:

- A new property search for the Australian site, written in AngularJS
- A UK stamp duty calculator (JavaScript/jQuery) http://www.knightfrank.co.uk/stamp-duty-calculator
- A new office and people search plugin (AngularJS, WebAPI)

Couchbase Inc. - Software Trainer (contract)

July 2015 - Present

I have trained some of Couchbase's customers in the use of the Couchbase C SDK (libcouchbase).

Tools/Languages: C++, Qt 5, libcouchbase, Qt Designer

These are one-day trainings which I have prepared together with an employee of Couchbase and held on-site in various locations. So far I've given this training four times to consistently positive feedback.

Horizon Strategic Partners Ltd – Senior Software Engineer

June 2015 - July 2015

I am porting a mobile application from Android to Windows Phone 8.1. The App interfaces a REST Service, downloads content to local storage and then displays the content in a WebView. When finished, the App will be available in the Windows Store.

Tools/Languages: C#, XAML, Windows Phone 8.1 API, Visual Studio 2013

Magnitude Internet GmbH – IT Director, Software Engineer

Oct 2014 – Present

I am the technical director of a German start-up company and responsible for architecture and development. The initial project of the company is an e-commerce web site. The web site is written using AngularJS with a WebAPI 2 back end. The first version is now live at www.paulfaehrtbus.de (in German). There is also an internal web site written in ASP MVC 5 and Entity Framework 6. The entire system is hosted on Azure and implemented with the Azure scaling mechanics in mind.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC 5, ASP Web API 2, AngularJS, MS Azure

HM Informatik AG – Senior Software Engineer (contract)

Mar 2014 – June 2015

I have written multiple plugins for a Flight Control Simulation software (FCS). These plugins mainly consisted of a user interface for data entry which then saved the data locally to XML. The plugins were also connected to an internal proprietary networking bus layer to synchronise the values through the network. The main challenge was to find a consistent architecture to avoid excessive code duplication over multiple similar plugins and of course writing performant and memory efficient C++.

Tools/Languages: C++, Boost, CMake, QT 4.8, Visual Studio 2010, Bazaar.

Vorward IT Services "Project Simple TrackR" - Senior Software Engineer / Architect Dec 2013 - Dec 2014

Simple TrackR is a simple to use family tracker app for Android. (It can be found at the Play Store at https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.vorwardit.tracker). The App is written using the latest Android KitKat (4.4) SDK while remaining compatible all the way down to Android Gingerbread (2.3.3) using the Android Support Library (AppCompat). The app is using Location Tacking and In-App-Billing provided by Google Play Services. It also uses Background Services, Google Maps API for Android. There was big emphasis on designing a modern UI using Actionbar and Navdrawer optimised for different display resolutions following the latest Style Guides from Google.

Tools/Languages: Android (KitKat SDK), Eclipse ADT, Google Maps for Android v2, In-App billing, Background services, Location Tracking

Momentum Coach Hire Ltd – IT Director, Senior Software Engineer, Consultant Sep 2011 – Mar 2014

I have been working for Momentum Coach Hire, a small ambitious company in the Coach Hire and Event Organisation business. There, I have created a variety of new web sites and improved existing ones. I've moved some of the existing ones to Azure, all the new ones were hosted on Azure from the start. I have also been promoted to IT Director and was responsible for the migration of the entire company (50 employees) onto Microsoft Office 365. Here is a list of projects and tools used:

- <u>www.momentumcoachhire.com</u> This was a pre-existing website. I have made heavy enhancements to the quote screen (click "Get A Coach Quote") using the **Google Maps API**
- www.momentumhub.com A website I have created from scratch with a very complex back office making heavy use of the Google Maps API. This site was created over the course of a year using ASP MVC 3, Entity Framework 4, MS SQL Server

- <u>www.grouproomscompare.com</u> A website I have created from scratch over the course of 2 months using ASP MVC 4, Entity Framework 5, MS SQL Server
- Other websites I have created a total of 9 web sites for Momentum using ASP MVC 3 or 4.
- **Email Migration** As part of my promotion to a Director of the company I have been entrusted with the migration of the company's email system to MS Office 365 and Microsoft hosted Exchange. The migration is currently underway.

Tools/Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC 3-4, Google Maps API, MS Azure

Symantec UK Ltd – Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2010 - Sep 2011

I have worked as a Senior Software Engineer for Symantec UK Ltd in the Research and Development team for Symantec Enterprise Vault, an email archiving solution written in C# and C++. In my time there I have performed the following tasks:

- Completed or am working on a number of small to medium projects including new features and architectural enhancements to improve resilience.
- For these projects, I have created the functional specification and software design documents and have implemented them on my own or as part of a team.
- Main tools/skills used:
 - OOA, OOD, Database Design, UML
 - MS Visual Studio 2008, C#, C++, XSLT, MS SQL Server 2008
- Fixed many defects in different code streams as part of learning the project architecture
- Received outstanding performance reviews for pro-actively driving architectural improvements and my excellent communication and team work

Ingres Europe Ltd – Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2008 - Feb 2010

With Ingres I worked as a permanently employed Consultant. I was involved in the following customer projects:

- Head Developer and Technical Team Lead for an open source project adding playback and recording capabilities to the Ingres database.
- Using the following skills/tools:
 - Heavy NPTL multi-threading on UNIX using C (tested with 1000s of threads)
 - GCC, GNU Automake, Netbeans IDE
 - Lexical processing in **C# running on .NET and Mono**
 - Ported from Linux to Solaris, HPUX, AIX, Windows
 - Held a presentation about it at the 2009 UK Ingres User Association
- Head Developer for porting the MS Excel based reporting for Newline Underwriting Ltd to Jasper Reports:
 - Working on site with the customer in an agile environment.
 - Talend Open Studio ETL, Jasper iReport
 - SQL Database Design and Implementation (Ingres Database)
 - SQL overnight number crunching scripts using BASH
 - Created a Data entry Website using Grails including user management and authentication
- Developer in a C# project for the MET Police.
- On site consulting at BNP Paribas

Thinking Instruments AG / Ingres Europe – Technical Team Lead, Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2004 - Aug 2008

Thinking Instruments is a very agile company focused on small to medium size customer projects. There were many projects being worked on simultaneously and I have fulfilled varying roles within them, like:

- Head Developer / Architect
- Technical Team Lead
- Project Manager
- Trainer

Within those roles, the following tasks are noteworthy:

- I was responsible for the full project Life Cycle. Statement of Work, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Integration, Support for multiple projects.
- Managed teams up to 5 people.
- Was responsible for the in-house migration from MS Visual SourceSafe to Subversion
- Managing according to the V-Model (German equivalent of PRINCE 2)
- Have given a lot of successful technical trainings with up to 20 trainees
- Given technical presentations at the CA Infoexchange 2004 and 2005 with audiences of 100+ people.

Technical Achievements:

- Lightweight open source ORM in C# using the .NET Reflection API
- Head Developer, Team Leader and SQL Database Architect for a Logistics Module for a large European CD/DVD manufacturer written in OpenROAD interfacing SAP/R3 using C++, C# and SOAP web services with an Ingres Database back end.
- I have been in the development team of the application for measuring and approval of ship licenses (MOT for ships) for the German Central Ship Inspection Commission (ZSUK). This Application was originally written in C++ and later ported to Java.
- As Head Developer and Team Leader for a Reporting tool for the German Armed Forces I created an interface to a live 3D simulation engine to gather statistics. **C#, SQL Database Design**.
- I have written a reporting server daemon which enables applications to use **Crystal Reports** through a very easy database API. Thinking Instruments was licensing this tool to several customers. The server was written in **C#**.

Morixs OHG – Software Engineer

Oct 2003 - Mar 2004

As a Software Developer I have worked in an agile team to implement an application for planning and accounting of medical services. The Framework was **Java J2SE with SAPDB as back end**. I was implementing mainly routines in the use-case and persistence layer of this very well structured application.

Technical University of Ilmenau – Student

Oct 1996 - Sep 2003

I have been fortunate enough to graduate with a Master's Degree in Computer Science from the Technical University of Ilmenau, Germany. The topic of my thesis was "Toolbox With Interactors For Modelling In Virtual Reality". I've created fast and reliable platform independent algorithms for 3D manipulation in Virtual and Augmented Reality as part of TU-Ilmenau's VRIB project (http://rabbit.prakinf.tu-ilmenau.de/new_vrib.html). One of them was a virtual "handles" interactor to manipulate basic objects in real time. Another one was a fast 3D snapping algorithm. This was done in OpenGL and C++ on top of a custom 3D modeller framework. On top

of my contribution to VRIB, I've completed several projects based on the OpenGL framework as Virtual Reality, Visualisation and Computer Graphics was my speciality subject next to Mathematics.

My thesis is mentioned on the page of the faculty: http://www.tu-ilmenau.de/en/computer-graphics-group/lehre/arbeiten/dmaa/#c115503.

ST Microelectronics – Intern

Oct 1999 - Mar 2000

As an Intern in ST Microelectronics I have implemented a new data transfer protocol (Digital Analog Lighting Interface, DALI) which was specified but no hardware circuitry existed. I have implemented a prototype using a programmable microcontroller in very low level C and a graphical frontend using VB. I was also in the team for a platform migration project for Nokia which took place in Tampere, Finland.

Education

Technical University of Ilmenau

- Diplom Informatiker (Dipl. Inf.) Equivalent to 2:1 Master in Computer Science
- Primary Subject: Computer Science "Good" (2.2)
- Secondary Subject: Mathematics "Good" (1.7)
- Diploma Thesis: "Toolbox with Interactors for Geometric Modelling in Virtual Reality" "Good" (2.3)
- Various extracurricular Activities like Manager of a Student Club.

Training received

Time	Content
Jan 2011	Effective C++
Jul 2010	Lotus Domino Administration Boot camp
Feb 2008	Application Development in OpenROAD
Jan 2008	Migrating ABF to OpenROAD
Dec 2007	Jaspersoft, iReport, JasperServer
Oct 2007	Visual Studio 2008, .NET 3.5
Jun 2005	V-Model XT
May 2005	QM System ISO 9001
Dec 2004	XSLT and XPath
Aug 2004	MS Project Server
Jul 2004	Train the Trainer
Apr 2004	QM System ISO 9001
Mar 2004	Ingres DBA

Interests

- Open Source Community, Linux
- Playing Guitar
- Racquet Sports

References

Excellent references available on request.